Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Public Schools records, 1833-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Public Schools Records
1833-2011
Ann Arbor Public Schools.
8534 Cc 2
The records of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, cover the numerous districts and schools that developed and then gradually merged into an area school system which today encompasses twenty-one elementary schools, five middle schools, and three high schools with a school population of 16,724 (as of May 17, 2005).
25 linear feet in 26 boxes.
231 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from Ann Arbor Public Schools (donor no. 6063 ) in multiple accessions.
The record group is open to research.
The first 'school' in Washtenaw County was an outdoor school held in the summer of 1825 near Platt Road, eventually replaced by a log cabin. In 1837 another log cabin school was erected in Pittsfield Township, at which site in 1953 would be built Meadowview School. The development of the schools in Pittsfield Township is well-documented in this collection, in the Pittsfield Township, 1833-1960 series.
Historically, schools grew from small population centers and then gradually merged and coalesced into larger systems. Small settlements grew into villages then to townships. There were annexations by Ann Arbor which brought rural school districts into the urban system. Events affecting population movements, such as World War I and World War II, impacted school development. State legislation would address the educational needs of growing areas as the demands for education grew over the decades.
The Ann Arbor Board of Education has almost continuous documentation through meeting minutes and Board agendas which reflect the organizational activities of the administration.
Researchers will notice that documentation is sometimes scattered and with gaps, but there is sufficient evidence of major events such as desegregation of the Ann Arbor Public Schools in the 1960's that gives a good picture of the times. Scrapbooks form a large part of the collection for the twentieth century for the period of 1933-1969. Clippings highlight not only school events and achievements, but also the events in the larger community that impact school policy.
Related collections are: Ann Arbor Public Schools Faculty Wives and Otto W. Haisley, who was superintendent in the 1920's. Researchers may also consult the Ann Arbor, Michigan photographic collection for photographs of schools. Pittsfield (Washtenaw County, Mich.) is a related collection that contains the earliest School district records for Pittsfield Township as held by the county, such as school census and annual reports, directors reports, and inspector's reports. A resource created in 2003, the Brown v. the Board of Education Archive, highlights desegregation in the Ann Arbor Schools and the Jones School closing. As of 2013 the link for this digital exhibit is: http://www.lib.umich.edu/brown-versus-board-education/. A History of Desegregation of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, 1954-1976 by Mary Jo Frank is available online (as of 2013) at http://name.umdl.umich.edu/AUS0335.0001.001
The collection consists of nine series: Ann Arbor Board of Education, 1838-1994; Ann Arbor Public Schools Historic Records, 1853-1970; Historic School District Records, 1865-1965; Pittsfield Township, 1833-1960; Administration, 1946-1982; Desegregation, 1965-1970; Scrapbooks, 1933-1969; Miscellaneous other records; 2012 Accession.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.). Board of Education.; Ann Arbor (Mich.: Township); Ann Arbor Public Schools.; Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Jones School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Pittsfield (Mich.: Township); Public schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; School integration--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor (Township); Schools--Michigan--Pittsfield (Township); Schools--Michigan--Scio (Township); Schools--Michigan--Superior (Washtenaw County: Township); Schools--Michigan--Webster (Township); Scio (Mich.: Township); Segregation in education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Superior (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township); Webster (Mich.: Township)
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Ann Arbor Public Schools.; Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Public schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; School administrators--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Contributors: Sound recordings
Butler, Leslie A.; West, Russell.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- Ann Arbor Board of Education, 1857-2011
  Ann Arbor Board of Education, 1857-2011 (AAPS) series includes agenda items for Board meetings, minutes, rules, a partial index to Board proceedings, and audio tapes with historical narratives.
  The 2012 Accession includes files on facility planning (2000-2004), bond/sinking fund (2004), new school (1998-2005), and miscellaneous topics notably a set of school dedication and anniversary programs and a series of three volumes containing students' writings in the early 1940s, mainly autobiographical and some relating to World War II experiences, by fifth graders at Angell, Eberbach, and an unidentified school.
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 20)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 21)
    (continued)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 22)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 23)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 24)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 25)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 26)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 27)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 28)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 29)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 30)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 31)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 32)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 33)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 34)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 35)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 36)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 37)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 38)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 39)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 40)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 41)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 42)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 43)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 44)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 45)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 46)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 47)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 48)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 49)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 50)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 51)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 52)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 53)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 54)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 55)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 56)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 57)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 58)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 59)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 60)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 61)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 62)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 63)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 64)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 65)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 66)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 67)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 68)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 69)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 70)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 71)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 72)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 73)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 74)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 75)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 76)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 77)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 78)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 79)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 80)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 81)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 82)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 83)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 84)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 85)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 86)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 87)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 88)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 89)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 90)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 91)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 92)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 93)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 94)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 95)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 96)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 97)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 98)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 99)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 100)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 101)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 102)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 103)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 104)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 105)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 106)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 107)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 108)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 109)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 110)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 111)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 112)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 113)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 114)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 115)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 116)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 117)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 118)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 119)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 120)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 121)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 122)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 123)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 124)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 125)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 126)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 127)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 128)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 129)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 130)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 131)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 132)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 133)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 134)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 135)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 136)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 137)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 138)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 139)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 140)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 141)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 142)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 143)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 144)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 145)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 146)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 147)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 148)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 149)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 150)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 151)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 152)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 153)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 154)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 155)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 156)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 157)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 158)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 159)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 160)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 161)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 162)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 163)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 164)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 165)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 166)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 167)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 168)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 169)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 170)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 171)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 172)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 173)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 174)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 175)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 176)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 177)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 178)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 179)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 180)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 181)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 182)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 183)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 184)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 185)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 186)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 187)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 188)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 189)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 190)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 191)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 192)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 193)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 194)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 195)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 196)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 197)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 198)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 199)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 200)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 201)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 202)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 203)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 204)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 205)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 206)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 207)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 208)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 209)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 210)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 211)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 212)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 213)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 214)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 215)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 216)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 217)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 218)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 219)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 220)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 221)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 222)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 223)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 224)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 225)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 226)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 227)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 228)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 229)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 230)
  - Board of Education Agenda, 1939-2011 (Volume 231)
  - History of the Ann Arbor Public Schools, 3 audiocassettes (Box 1)
    (recorded May 1978 narrated by Russell West)
  - Index to Proceedings of Ann Arbor Board of Education, 1857-1931 (Box 1)
  - Interview with Dr. Leslie Butler, Superintendent of Schools, 1920-1925; 1 audiocassettes (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 1)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 2)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 3)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 4)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 5)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 6)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 7)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 8)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 9)
  - Minutes, 1857-1949 (Volume 10)
  - Partial Rules of Board of Education, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Facility Planning (Box 20)
    - Report to the Superintendent, September 27, 2000 (Box 20)
    - High School Facility Planning Feasibility Report, September, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Facility Master Plan, January 2004 (Box 20)
    - Facilities Recommendation -- Vol. 1-3, January 2004 (Box 20)
    - Facilities Recommendation -- Vol. 4, February 2004 (Box 20)
    - Comprehensive Facilities Recommendation (Box 21)
      - Volume 1, January 9, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 2, January 28, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 3, January 30, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 4, February 6, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 5, February 20, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 6, February 27, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 7, March 5, 2004 (Box 21)
      - Volume 8, March 19, 2004 (Box 21)
  - Bond/Sinking Fund
    - Proposal, March 26, 2004 (Box 21)
    - Bond Application Revisions, April 26, 2004 (Box 21)
    - Briefing Book, June 14, 2004 (Box 21)
    - Application for Preliminary Qualification of Bonds, June 14, 2004 (Box 21)
  - New School
    - High School Futures Committee, November 1998 (Box 21)
    - Program Description and Curriculum Overview, August 1999 (Box 21)
    - Evaluation of the First Three Years of the New School Pilot Program, 1996-January 20, 1999 (Box 21)
    - Maple Road High School Traffic Study Data, November 2, 2004 (Box 22)
    - Design Development Focus Groups, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Ann Arbor High School, Class of Memorabilia, 1943 (Box 23)
    - Ann Arbor Natural Community
      - Census of, May 1936 (Box 23)
      - Enrollment Book, December 1936 (Box 23)
    - Ann Arbor Union High School, History (Box 23)
    - Annual Statistical Report, 1882 (Box 23)
    - Articles of Incorporation & Reincorporation of School District #1, 1865 (Box 23)
    - Coalition for Racial Justice, October 1968 (Box 23)
    - Council, February 28 May 1, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Education Extension, June 1898 (Box 23)
    - Humaneness in Education, January 20, 1971 (Box 23)
    - Index of the Proceedings of the Ann Arbor Board of Education, 1857-1931 (Box 23)
    - Petitions to the Board of Education
      - (Bayliss Drive), 1959-1960 (Box 23)
      - 1946-1965 (Box 23)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 23)
      - (includes letters, etc.), 1966-1967 (Box 23)
      - 1967-1968, 3 folders (Box 23)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 23)
      - 1968-1970 (Box 23)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 23)
      - The Reporter, December 1950 (Box 23)
    - Review of School Sites, Part IV, Ann Arbor Schools Study, 1974 (Box 24)
    - SISS Programs and Services, June 2005 (Box 24)
    - Graduate Follow-up Surveys, Washtenaw County High Schools and Ann Arbor Schools, Classes of 1999, 2003 released 2005 (Box 24)
    - Study of Disproportionality and Over-Representation in Special Education, May 15, 2006 (Box 24)
    - Strategic Planning Information, 2006-2007 (Box 24)
    - Leap the Gap, Youth Empowerment Project, June 2007 (Box 24)
    - Community Responses from Online Budget Survey & Budget Forums, December 2009-January 2010 (Box 24)
    - Students' Writings by Fifth Grade Students
      - "All of Us," Eberbach School (includes photographs), 1944 (Box 24)
      - "Monday Morning," school unidentified, 1942-1944 (Box 24)
      - "Stories I Like," Angell School, 1945 (Box 24)
    - Anniversary (Box 25)
      - Haisley Elementary, March 1979 (Box 25)
      - Huron High School, May 1993 (Box 25)
      - Pittsfield School District, 1927-1951 (Box 25)
      - Stone School, 1826-1986 (Box 25)
    - Building/Bond Programs (Box 25)
    - Building Needs, Survey, November 1948 (Box 25)
    - Building Projects Complete Since 64, October 19, 1955 (Box 25)
    - CAM Magazine, November 1994 (Box 25)
    - Ceremony, Roberto Clemente, March 1993 (Box 25)
    - Dedication
      - Abbot Elementary, October 1962 (Box 25)
      - Administrative Officers, AAPS, September 1957 (Box 25)
      - Allen Elementary, April 1961 (Box 25)
      - Angell Elementary, November 1977 (Box 25)
      - Ann Arbor Public Library, October 1957; October 1974 (Box 25)
      - Ann Arbor Senior High School, April 1956 (Box 25)
      - Bach School, March 1958 (Box 25)
      - Bader Elementary, December 1965 (Box 25)
      - Balas Building, October 1974 (Box 25)
      - Bryant, October 1973; November 1982 (Box 25)
      - Carpenter School, February 1953 (Box 25)
      - Clague Middle School (Box 25)
      - Clinton Elementary, May 1968 (Box 25)
      - Dicken School (Box 25)
      - Forsythe Junior High School, May 1960 (Box 25)
      - Freeman Elementary, November 1976 (Box 25)
      - Huron High School, November 1969 (Box 25)
      - Lakewood Elementary, April 1961; October 1962 (Box 25)
      - Lawton Elementary School, October 1964 (Box 25)
      - Logan Elementary, May 1977 (Box 25)
      - Loving Branch Library, September 1965 (Box 25)
      - Mack Elementary, January 1975 (Box 25)
      - Martin Luther King, Jr. School, November 1994 (Box 25)
      - Meadowview Elementary, September 1953 (Box 25)
      - Mitchell Elementary, June 1952 (Box 25)
      - Newport Elementary, January 1968 (Box 25)
      - Pattengill Elementary, September 1957 (Box 25)
      - Scarlett Junior High School, May 1969 (Box 25)
      - Slauson and Open House, October 1978 (Box 25)
      - Thurston Elementary, October 25, 1964 (Box 25)
      - Transportation Building, November 1982 (Box 25)
      - Wines Elementary (Box 25)
    - Directory, Ann Arbor Public Schools, 1979-80 (Box 25)
    - Report, Completing the Grade Schools, April 1924 (Box 25)
- Ann Arbor Public Schools Historic Records, 1853-1970
  Ann Arbor Public Schools Historic Records, 1853-1970 series contains a wide range of documents and volumes covering administration, school elections, statistics from Ann Arbor schools primarily in the early history of the system. The content of the series is scattered, but has many unique historic notebooks and records that give a view into the operations of the original system and how it evolved.
  - Administration
    - Accounting
      - Accounting System Manual of Instruction, 1931 (Box 1)
        (including 1934 revision)
      - Ann Arbor High School General activities, receipts, 1923-1928; 2 volumes (Box 1)
      - Book of Accounts, 1929-1931; 1 volumes (Box 1)
      - Journal for Correction of Charges on Ledger, 1930; 1 volumes (Box 1)
      - Record of Insurance Policies, School District No. 1 Ann Arbor City, 1907-1911; 1 volumes (Box 1)
    - Annual and Special Meetings, District 11
      - 1853-1911 (Volume 11)
      - 1911-1933 (Volume 12)
    - Association for Childhood Education International, 1949-1951 (Box 1)
    - Athletic Records, 1910 (Volume 13)
    - Audit Reports, 1936; 1947 (Box 1)
    - Data from and pertaining to the Ann Arbor Public Schools